<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exploring the Dataset in Tableau  on Dremio Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exploring the Dataset in Tableau  on Dremio Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing count of records by Date</title>
      <link>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/751-review-count.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/751-review-count.html</guid>
      <description>Navigate back to your Tableau Online Workbook which should still show the count of NYC_Taxi records.
  Count the records by pickup date by dragging the pickup_date dimension to the column bar. Tableau is now showing the count of records for each year in the dataset.
 Let’s get a little more granular with the data by examining the data by month. Hover over the blue YEAR(pickup_date) and click the dropdown arrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does Month Impact Surcharge</title>
      <link>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/752-impact-month.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/752-impact-month.html</guid>
      <description>Clear your Tableau sheet by pressing the button on the Tableau toolbar and selecting “Clear Sheet” .  Now you are going to examine how each month of the year impacts the surcharge of a taxi ride. To do this first you are going to drag “Pickup_Date” to the columns bar and select Month from the drop down.   **Remember we are looking for the sum for each month not a month over month comparison** Now drag the surcharge measure to the rows bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing the Jobs in Dremio</title>
      <link>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/753-review-jobs.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/75-exploring-dataset-in-tableau/753-review-jobs.html</guid>
      <description>  Navigate back to your Dremio UI and click on the jobs tab.    Everytime you change a parameter or add a field to your Tableau analysis, Tableau passes back a SQL query for Dremio to perform. You can see all of the jobs that have run in Dremio. Notice the duration is </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>