<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Explore Dremio Home Screen on Dremio Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/20-explore-dremio.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explore Dremio Home Screen on Dremio Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/20-explore-dremio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore Dremio Home Screen</title>
      <link>/20-explore-dremio/201-dremio-home-screen.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20-explore-dremio/201-dremio-home-screen.html</guid>
      <description>Explore Dremio Home Screen The Dremio Home screen has 4 major areas:  Home Space The Home Space is a private user work area that can contain both physical and virtual datasets. Uploaded files promoted to a physical dataset are stored in the home space. Data can be curated in the home space until its ready to be shared by moving it to a shared space. Spaces Spaces are shared locations for saving virtual datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a folder in your personal space</title>
      <link>/20-explore-dremio/202-creating-a-folder-in-your-personal-space.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20-explore-dremio/202-creating-a-folder-in-your-personal-space.html</guid>
      <description>Creating a folder in your personal space   From the Dremio home screen, click the folder icon at the top right of the Home Space.   Provide a name to the folder and click Save Note: You can use this folder to save any Physical Datasets (PDS) or Virtual Datasets (VDS) that you create during this workshop.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a Space to collaborate with other users</title>
      <link>/20-explore-dremio/203-set-up-a-space-to-collaborate-with-other-users.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20-explore-dremio/203-set-up-a-space-to-collaborate-with-other-users.html</guid>
      <description>Set up a Space to collaborate with other users   From the Dremio home screen click the &#34;+&#34; icon next to “Spaces” .   Provide a name for your Space and click Save   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore the different data connections that Dremio supports</title>
      <link>/20-explore-dremio/204-explore-the-different-data-connections-that-dremio-supports.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/20-explore-dremio/204-explore-the-different-data-connections-that-dremio-supports.html</guid>
      <description>Explore the different data connections that Dremio supports   Under “Data Lakes”  in the bottom left corner of the Dremio home screen, click &#34;+&#34; icon. You will see a list of the various Table Stores &amp; File Stores that Dremio natively supports. We will be using this to create a connection to an AWS S3 data source in a later step.   Under “External Sources” in the bottom left corner of the Dremio home screen click &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>