<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Create Virtual Dataset on Dremio Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Create Virtual Dataset on Dremio Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/50-create-virtual-datasets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Virtual Dataset from the Data Lake Storage</title>
      <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets/501-create-virtual-dataset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50-create-virtual-datasets/501-create-virtual-dataset.html</guid>
      <description>From your Dremio Home Screen, click on your AWS S3 Storage Connection labeled “AWS S3 Modernization Workshop” on the bottom left corner of your screen. In the top center portion of your screen you will see a folder with the name “dremio-data-lake-AccountID”. Click on that folder then click &#34;dremioworkshopdata&#34; folder and then click on the “Trips” Folder. You should now see Parquet files.   In Dremio you can convert a folder of files into a single Physical Dataset (PDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Tags and Details to Dataset Catalog. </title>
      <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets/502-add-tags-dataset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50-create-virtual-datasets/502-add-tags-dataset.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you have saved your VDS a couple additional tabs will appear on the top of your Preview Window. They are Catalog &amp; Reflection. Navigate to the “Catalog” tab within your NYC_Taxi VDS.  The Catalog tab acts as a wiki allowing you and others that have access, to document and share information pertaining to the specific Virtual Dataset. Here you can post information about the dataset, updates that have been made, owners and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Creating a Calculated Field</title>
      <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets/503-create-calculated-field.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50-create-virtual-datasets/503-create-calculated-field.html</guid>
      <description>Navigate back to the Data Tab for your NYC_Taxi dataset and look at the different fields in the dataset.  The field titled  “trip_distance”  is a float field that shows the distance of each trip in miles. What if someone who wanted to use this dataset wanted to know the trip distance in kilometers? With Dremio, you can create a calculated field. Click the downward arrow next to the “trip_distance” field and then click on “Calculated Field”  From the  “Add Calculated Field”  page you can use SQL functions to create or replace fields in the Dremio Virtual Dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing a Virtual Dataset</title>
      <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets/504-edit-vitual-dataset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50-create-virtual-datasets/504-edit-vitual-dataset.html</guid>
      <description>From the Dremio home screen hover over the NYC_Taxi Dataset and click on the edit button. This will allow you to edit an already existing VDS.
  Notice the fields pickup_datetime &amp;amp; dropoff_datetime include both the date and time as one value. For the purposes of this lab, we just need to keep the date.
  Dremio provides different ways to separate and remove values from a specific field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Data Reflection</title>
      <link>/50-create-virtual-datasets/505-set-reflection.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/50-create-virtual-datasets/505-set-reflection.html</guid>
      <description>Reflections are physically optimized representations of source data that Dremio maintains in order to accelerate query performance. Dremio can accelerate a query by utilizing one or more Data Reflections to partially or entirely satisfy that query, rather than processing the raw data in the underlying data source. There are various types of Data Reflections:    Raw reflections – A raw reflection includes one or more fields from the anchor dataset, sorted, partitioned and distributed by specific fields.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>