<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Explore the dataset on Dremio Modernization Workshop</title>
    <link>/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explore the dataset on Dremio Modernization Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Dataset</title>
      <link>/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets/401-finding-dataset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets/401-finding-dataset.html</guid>
      <description>Dremio’s integrated data catalog allows us to search for datasets by simply typing a string in the search box. Once we type in the string, it will automatically provide a list of available datasets matching our search term.  Navigate to the “Search Catalog” bar at the top of the screen. In the search catalog box, enter Taxi. You should return a result that matches this: Hover over the green grid icon, until you see and then click on the “i”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Dataset</title>
      <link>/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets/402-exploring-dataset.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/40-explore-data-create-virtual-datasets/402-exploring-dataset.html</guid>
      <description>Now that we have selected a dataset to explore, let’s take a look at the different aspects of the Data Preview screen   5 regions in the image are described below:  Shows the dataset that is being used Dremio provides the ability to write specific SQL functions, add or remove columns and join datasets. We will explore this in greater detail later in the workshop. Is the preview window to the current dataset and the fields that the dataset contains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>